

**♥** Edinburgh, Scotland

□ +447460113410 | 

theoxolausson@gmail.com | 

https://theoxo.xyz | 

theoxolausson@gmail.com | 

https://theoxo.xyz | 

theoxolausson@gmail.com | 

https://theoxo.xyz | 

theoxolausson@gmail.com | 

https://theoxo.xyz | 

http



## Summary\_

Master of Informatics student at the University of Edinburgh with an exceptional academic record (4.0 GPA) and experience in research. Interested in applying mathematical techniques to problems in computer science, ranging from applications in machine learning to the design of parallel computer architectures.



**Arm Research** 

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

RESEARCH INTERN, MEMORY & SYSTEMS ARCHITECTURE

Cambridge, UK Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- · Designed, analysed and implemented a method for verifying the memory persistency model of Arm's ARMv8 architecture on real hardware
- Used this method to construct a suite of Litmus tests targeting different aspects of the memory model
- · Discussed my progress in weekly team-wide meetings, and regularly met with senior members of staff to discuss complex aspects of my research
- Gave a 60-minute presentation on the results of my research, open to all research staff at Arm

#### Institute for Computing Systems Architecture, Univ. of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, UK

RESEARCH INTERN/ASSISTANT

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Worked on extending ProtoGen, a tool for automatically generating directory cache coherence protocols from atomic specifications (as seen at the International Symposium on Computer Architecture, Los Angeles, 2018)
- · Researched algorithmic approaches to the localization of bugs in coherence protocols, implementing and analysing several potential methods
- · Extended the DSL of ProtoGen and wrote a parser for the output of its Murphi verification backend
- Currently continuing this work as my undergraduate dissertation



## Education \_\_\_\_\_\_

**University of Edinburgh** 

Edinburgh, UK

## MASTER OF INFORMATICS (HONS), EXPECTED FIRST CLASS

Sep. 2016 - CURRENTLY

- 5-year integrated Masters programme, starting off following the same path as the BSc in Artificial Intelligence & Computer Science but then diverging into study at the Masters level
- Grade average: A2 (UK), 4.0 (US)
- Course highlights from the Fall 2019 semester:
  - Machine Learning Practical: Used PyTorch and Python to build and analyse Deep Learning systems based on recent advances in the literature. For example, compared the effects of adding Batch Normalization or the DenseNet topology to a 38-layer CNN by conducting experiments evaluating the model's performance on the CIFAR-100 image recognition dataset.
- Machine Learning & Patter Recognition: Developed a deep understanding of the mathematics underlying modern approaches to machine learning. I especially enjoyed working with Bayesian regression and Gaussian Processes.



#### Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Python C/C++ Kotlin Java OCaml Haskell

TOOLS/FRAMEWORKS Git VCS Linux PyTorch sk-learn Murphi (model checking) JUnit/Espresso testing

THEORY Deep Learning Neural Networks Computer Vision Memory Models Computer Architecture Algorithms/Data Structures

**LANGUAGES** English (fluent) Swedish (Fluent)

# Awards\_\_\_\_\_

2019	Informatic BDEs prize for Entrepreneurship, System Design Project 2018/19 (Univ. of Edinburgh)	Edinburgh, UK
2010	Sky Prize for Teamwork, System Decign Project 2019/10 (Univ. of Edinburgh)	Edinburah IIK

**Sky Prize for Teamwork**, System Design Project 2018/19 (Univ. of Edinburgh)

2017 €2500 Grant for Pursuing Further Education Abroad, Hempel Foundation 2016 €3000 Grant for Pursuing Further Education Abroad, Hempel Foundation

2016 £200 Award for Top Academic Performance, Ehrensvärdska High School Edinhurah IIK

Copenhagen, DK

Copenhagen, DK

Karlskrona, SE